两周前
Two weeks ago,
一个隐形穹顶罩住了切斯特磨坊镇
an invisible dome crashed down on Chester's Mill,
使我们与世隔绝
cutting us off from the rest of the world.
为什么穹顶会在这里  以后还会有什么谜团
Why the dome is here or what mysteries lie ahead,
我们依然一无所知
we still don't know.
每天它都考验我们的极限
Every day it tests our limits,
激发我们内心最善和最恶一面
bringing out the best and the worst in us.
有人说我们会永远困在这里
Some say we'll be stuck here forever,
但我们会一直奋力寻找出路
but we will never stop fighting to find a way out.
你找山姆干什么
Why are you looking for Sam?
我觉得他一直认识梅兰妮
I think he's known who Melanie is all along.
我还在想你什么时候会出现呢
I was wondering when you'd show up.
你不怕人们看见我们在一起吗
Aren't you afraid of people seeing us together?
你25年前做了保证
You made a promise 25 years ago,
确保我们埋葬的不会重见天日
to make sure that what we buried stayed buried.
你是来放我出去的
You came to set me free.
我妈妈说你有答案  我想知道
My mother said you had answers; I want them.
我不会再回去了
I'm out for good now.
那些是手指印
Those are the fingertips of a hand--
似乎安琪也留下了一点凶手的战利品
Looks like Angie got a piece of whoever did this to her.
你觉得莱尔就是消失在这里了吗
Do you think this is where Lyle disappeared to?
这是个隧道
It's a tunnel.
你想杀了我们
You tried to us all!
茱莉亚  我没做
Julia, I didn't do it.
大个儿吉姆和丽贝卡想做的事
What Big Jim and Rebecca tried to do
没有借口
is inexcusable...
但并非不可原谅
...but it's not unforgivable.
我觉得她管理切斯特磨坊镇管理得很好
...I think she's done a hell of a job running Chester's Mill.
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：加森  送小孩  圈圈  michael  roaddog  面条  冰蓝
■
校对：冰蓝     时间轴：大喷子  薛定谔的猫  小萌  小雨
后期：冰蓝     总监：冰蓝
■
你看到什么了
What do you see?
地下室
Basement.
我甚至不知道学校里还有这种地方
I didn't know it was even under this part of school.
看见莱尔了吗
Any sign of Lyle?
这里有脚印
There's footprints.
朝着这个隧道去了
They're heading up into this tunnel.
小心点
Be careful.
芭比现在是警长了  也许...
Barbie's sheriff now, maybe...
莱尔杀死了安琪
Lyle killed Angie.
我追踪他来到这里  我要亲自来追他
I tracked him down here. I'm doing this.
还有我
Not alone.
一定要平安回来
Please come back.
莱尔很危险
Lyle's dangerous.
不会让他再危险多久了
Not for long.
我需要借一下你的普瑞斯车
I need to borrow your Prius.
你要去找莱尔吗
You going looking for Lyle?
是啊  只要他还逍遥法外
Yeah. Well, as long as he's out there on the loose,
他就是我的麻烦
he's my problem.
今晚不清查几次我是不会睡觉的
I'm not gonna sleep tonight unless I do a few more sweeps.
你已经有警长的样子了
Being sheriff already looks good on you.
还有  如果你跟山姆说话
Also, if you talk to Sam,
用对讲机联系我
get ahold of me on the walkie,
因为我也有问题想问他
'cause I want to question him, too.
关于梅兰妮吗
About Melanie?
梅兰妮  安琪
Melanie, Angie,
他一天都在做什么
what he's been doing all day.
我不是指责他
I'm not pointing any fingers.
我只是想考虑所有的可能性
I'm just trying to explore all the options.
小心点
Be careful.
我还以为你跟乔和诺莉待在一起
I thought you were with Joe and Norrie.
他们回家了
They went home.
他们生我的气了  我做了一件傻事
They're mad at me. I did something stupid.
你想告诉我是什么事吗
You want to tell me what?
我和乔接吻了
I kissed Joe.
我知道
I know.
我只是想做一会正常人
I just wanted to feel normal for a minute.
梅兰妮  你就是正常人
Melanie, you are normal.
我死过
I died.
我的一切都不正常
Nothing about me is normal.
为什么我还留在世上
Why am I even here?
因为我跟某个蛋联系到一起了吗
Because I'm connected to some egg?
甚至没人知道那个蛋在哪
And no one even knows where it is.
事实上  我知道
Actually, I do.
我在发现你的几分钟之前把它扔到了湖里
I dropped it in the lake a few minutes before I found you.
你为什么要这么做
Why'd you do that?
因为穹顶想让我那样做
Because the dome wanted me to.
它选择了我
It chose me.
而且我认为它把你带回世上是有原因的
And I think it brought you back for a reason.
什么原因
What reason?
我不知道
I don't know.
只是一个吻  我很抱歉
It was only one kiss! I'm sorry!
但是这不仅仅是你亲了她
But it's not just that you kissed her!
梅兰妮来了以后  所有的事都围着她转
Ever since Melanie got here, everything's been about her!
就像没有我们了
It's like there's no us anymore.
但是有啊
But there is!
我爱你  诺莉
I love you, Norrie.
真遗憾
Too bad.
我不爱你
I don't love you.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
那我为什么还要留在这里
Why should I stay here then?
大个儿吉姆不是我的家人
Big Jim's not my family.
卡罗琳也不是
Or Carolyn.
如果你不爱我
If you don't love me,
那么你为什么还要我在这里  是不是
then why would you want me around here, right?
是的
Right.
感觉不错吧  公正对待镇民
It's a good feeling, isn't it? Doing right by the town.
我喜欢那种感觉
I love that feeling.
你很少能享受到
You've had it so rarely.
对  你迟早会令他们失望的
Yeah, well, you'll disappoint them soon enough.
你想吓唬我吗  吉姆
You trying to rattle me, Jim?
只是不想让你得意忘形
Just don't want you to feel too good about yourself.
你和我都知道这个镇子属于谁
You and I both know whose town this is.
不属于你
It's not yours.
不属于我
It's not mine.
我要做的第一件事就是还政于民
And the first thing I'm gonna do is give it back to them.
"还政于民"
"Give it back to them"?
投票
Voting.
他们有权表决自己身上发生的事
These people are entitled to a say in what happens to them.
有趣  你要把一座危镇
That's interesting. You're gonna put a town on the brink
放在恐惧  绝望的人民手里吗
in the hands of scared, desperate people?
你的秀发下有脑子吗
Is there a brain under that hair?
这帮人不需要谈论感受
These people don't need to talk about their feelings.
他们需要被领导
They need to be led.
我帮你和丽贝卡说服了"这帮人"
I did you and Rebecca a favor by convincing "These people"
别绞死你们
not to string you two up.
别测试我的耐心
Don't test my patience.
这座镇子没有暴动的真正原因是
The only reason this town didn't riot
我握了你的手
is 'cause I took your hand.
半个镇子属于我  你别忘了
Half this town is mine. Don't you forget that.
你知道你的女友在做什么吗
Hey, you hear what your girlfriend's doing?
她要让人们对每个重大决定投票
She's putting every major town decision to a vote.
让我们无所事事  眼睁睁看着罗马焚毁
Let us twiddle our thumbs while Rome burns.
据我所知  投票是一项权利
Last I heard, voting was a right.
告诉她这是个坏主意
Yeah, well, tell her it's a bad idea.
她不听我的
She won't listen to me.
这证明她很聪明
That's a wise woman.
听着  芭比
Look, Barbie.
每次遇到大事  我们都站在同一战线
You and I have been on the same side when it counts.
吉姆  谁告诉茱莉亚
Hey, Jim, who told Julia that I was in
我支持灭绝计划的
on this whole extermination plan?
每次我对你心存希望
See, every time I've given you the benefit of the doubt,
都会自食其果
it bites me in the ass.
现在  我不会惹茱莉亚
Now, I'm not gonna cross Julia.
如果你敢惹  我可不会像她一样宽容
And if you try to, I'm not gonna be as forgiving as she is.
芭比  你在吗
Barbie, you there?
芭比
Barbie?
我在  请讲  丽贝卡
Yeah, go ahead, Rebecca.
我在学校
I'm at the high school.
山姆和小詹姆斯在追捕莱尔
Sam and Junior are tracking Lyle.
-你最好快来  -来了
- You'd better get here. - On my way.
莱尔必须炸开储物柜后部才能下来
Lyle had to bust out the back of the locker to get down here.
我们肯定已经走了一英里了
We must be a half a mile in by now.
你想回就回吧
You want to go back, go back.
我不需要你帮忙对他开枪
I don't need your help shooting him.
听着  小詹姆斯  我知道你爱安琪
Look, Junior, I know you loved Angie,
但是杀人不是儿戏
but killing someone is no small thing.
你杀过吗
You've done that?
当然没有
Of course not.
克林特·邓迪对安琪动手动脚
Clint Dundee put his hands all over Angie.
我找到了他  然后一枪穿心
I hunted him down and shot him in the heart.
我很感谢你照顾我  但莱尔今天必须死
I appreciate you looking after me, but Lyle's dying today.
有点紧张啊
A little jumpy.
别拿枪指着我了  小詹姆斯
Now, you want to stop pointing that thing at me, Junior?
山姆
Sam.
好久不见
Been awhile.
人们在找你
People looking for you.
是啊  我挺忙
Yeah, I've been busy.
我不能让小詹姆斯独自追捕一个疯子
I'm not gonna let Junior hunt for a lunatic by himself.
我走了
I'm moving on.
你先走吧
You go on ahead.
我断后
I'm just gonna hang back.
确保我们不会被别人偷袭
You know, make sure no one else sneaks up on us.
我妈妈的日记
My mom's journal.
小詹姆斯  停下
Junior, stop!
小詹姆斯  当心
Junior, look out!
芭比  小心
Barbie! Watch out!
穹顶之下  第二季第六集
山姆  你没事吧
Sam, you okay?
被砸了  但没事
Oh! Bashed up, but all right.
小詹姆斯
Junior!
小詹姆斯  你还好吗
Junior, you okay?!
留在那里  我去找人帮忙
Stay there! I'll get some help!
天呐
God...
你的头在流血
Your head's bleeding.
本可能会更糟
It could've been worse.
感谢你推了我一把
Thanks for the push.
是啊
Yeah.
我觉得这是莱尔干的
I think Lyle did this.
小镇理发师会做炸药吗
The town barber makes bombs?
他一直诡计多端
He's always been a crafty guy.
而且自从穹顶落下以后
And he's gone crazier than a rat in a jar
他比笼中困鼠还疯狂
since the dome came down.
他很聪明  会用日记作为陷阱诱饵
He's smart enough to bait the trap with the journal.
我们不能原路返回了
Well, we're not getting out the way we came.
看来我们要走那条路了
Guess we'll try that way.
你先
After you.
别动好吗
Just-just stay still, okay?
就是这样
There you go.
你觉得跟那个酒鬼一起下去是个好主意吗
You thought it was a good idea to go down there with that drunk?
他为我做的事比你做的还多
He's done more for me than you ever did.
你来干什么  又没人叫你
What are you even doing here? Nobody called you.
我去哪里你管不着
I don't need your permission to go here or anywhere else.
吉姆  消停消停好吗  我在给你儿子包扎呢
Jim, give it a rest, okay? I'm trying to bandage your son.
发生什么事了
What happened?
我听到你通过对讲机找芭比了  他人呢
I heard you radio Barbie. Where is he?
我和山姆在追踪莱尔
Sam and I were tracking down Lyle.
芭比来找我们  然后突然
Barbie came after us, and then all of a sudden,
我被什么绊了一下  下面就塌了
I tripped on something and then there was a cave-in.
你们进这个储物柜里面了吗
You went through this locker?
他们人呢  他们没事吧
Where are they? Are they all right?!
我不知道
I don't know.
下面有很多石头和杂物把路堵住了
There's a bunch of rocks and stuff blocking them in.
我们得把他们救出来
We have to get them out of there.
你们没注意吗
In case you have noticed,
我们还有更严重的问题要处理
we've got bigger problems than those two.
一定是红雨中的酸性物质破坏了表层土壤
The acidity in the red rain must have fried the topsoil.
现在这玩意儿被吹的到处都是
Yeah, well, it's blowing around everywhere
把什么都覆盖住了
and coating everything,
包括穹顶里面
including the inside of the dome.
穹顶是半透明的
Which is semi-permeable.
如果穹顶壁被遮挡住
If the dome walls get clogged,
空气就进不来了
no air's gonna be able to get in.
那我们都会窒息而亡  所有人都会
And then we suffocate. All of us.
我们还有多长时间
How long until that happens?
我们也可以采取措施的  好吗
There are steps we can take, okay?
水雾扩散
Mist dispersal.
尽快把水撒到空中让尘土落地
Get water into the air as quickly as possible to ground the dust.
用消防水管  风扇  或者是大型风车
Fire hose, fan, uh, a giant windmill, maybe.
我以前让孩子们制作过一些
I had the kids working on some,
但我得把这事放了一放
but I had to put it on the back burner.
不过我们还有一切制作材料
We still have all the materials, though.
至少你的主意比茱莉亚的有用多了
At least your idea is doing more than Julia's to help.
你就是想眼睁睁看着芭比和山姆死
You just want to see Barbie and Sam dead.
那一切都取决于我了是吧
So, I guess it's up to me, then, huh?
他们可能在老水泥厂里面
You know, they could be in part of the old cement factory.
我们去找隧道的地图
We find a map of the tunnel system,
可能会找到其它入口
we might find another way in.
你能找到地图吗
Can you find one?
当然了
Yeah, sure.
莱尔可能已经出来了
Lyle might have already gotten out.
根本无从得知他是不是还在里面
There's no way of knowing if he's down there anymore.
他在外面总比在里面对付芭比和山姆强
Better he's out here than hunting Barbie and Sam down there.
但是他要是在外面  也同样危险
Yeah, but if he's back up here, he's just as dangerous.
我跟山姆发现莱尔的目标不止是安琪
Sam and I found out that Lyle wasn't just after Angie.
他想杀四只手
He's after the four hands.
他怎么知道四只手的事的
How does he know about the hands?
很久以前我妈妈画了一幅我们托着穹顶的画
My mom drew a picture of us holding up the dome way back when.
莱尔以为要是我们死了  被提就会到来
Now, Lyle thinks that if we're dead, the Rapture comes.
也就是说他也想杀你吗
So, he wanted to kill you, too?
对  他知道我会追踪他
Yeah. He knew I'd follow him.
我确定隧道里面的炸弹目标是我
I'm pretty sure that bomb down there was meant for me.
我们得确保乔和诺莉的安全
We need to make sure Joe and Norrie are safe.
我去
I'll do that.
-小心点  -我跟他一起去
- Be careful. - I'll go with him.
梅兰妮  我不...
Melanie, I don't...
他们也是我的朋友
They're my friends, too.
我要去
I'm going.
我会保护她的  我保证
I'll make sure she's safe, I promise.
你从小就认识莱尔对吗
So, you known Lyle all your life, right?
对  我们从小一起长大
Yeah, we were friends growing up.
最近你听说过或者见过什么
You hear or seen anything recently
让你觉得是他杀了安琪吗
makes you think he may have killed Angie?
我很多年没见他了
I haven't seen him in years.
但是他绑架过丽贝卡
But between kidnapping Rebecca,
打过小詹姆斯  所以一切合情合理
clocking Junior and all that-- makes sense.
那你们为什么后来不是朋友了
So, then, why'd you guys stop being friends?
出什么事了吗
Something happen?
没有  有时候人跟人就是渐行渐远了
Nope. Sometimes people just grow apart.
你觉得该走哪边
You got a preference?
你左  我右
You go left, I got right,
这样搜寻面积大点
we cover more ground?
这么快就烦我了吗
You tired of me already?
我莫名其妙就特别烦你看我  嗯
I'm tired of you eyeing me for no reason, yeah.
你怎么这么安静
You're awfully quiet.
我害怕  你不怕吗
I'm scared. Aren't you?
没事的
It's okay.
你听到我跟茱莉亚说的了  我答应会保护你的
You heard what I told Julia. I promise I'd keep you safe.
你跟山姆年轻的时候真像
You look so much like Sam when he was younger.
梅兰妮  你这是怎么了
Melanie, what the hell is going on with you?
我得跟你说一件...
I have to tell you something...
疯狂的事
crazy.
我觉得...
I think...
当时是莱尔杀的我
Lyle's who killed me.
快  快点进来
Come on, come on! Get inside.
大家都快点到里面来
Come on, everyone, get inside!
穹顶壁已经被挡住了
The dome's walls are already plugging up.
空气都进不来了
No air's gonna be able to get through.
要是我们现在不行动  我们都会被憋死的
And if we don't act now, we're all gonna choke to death.
空气太热太干了
The air is too hot and dry.
但是如果我们齐心协力
But I know that if we work together,
我们的计划就能成功
we can make this plan happen.
我们可以做一个丽贝卡·佩恩班里做的那种风车
We can make a windmill like Rebecca Pine's class was building.
这样我们就能把水吹到空气中去
And we can use it to fan water through the air and that'll...
水里有什么  吉姆
And what's in the water, Jim?
另一种病毒吗
Another virus?
你觉得我是轻易做出那个决定的吗
Do you think I made that decision lightly?
我把我自己和我儿子的生命置于危险之中
I put my own life at risk. My son's life at risk.
我只是在努力帮助大家度过这场难关
I'm just trying like hell to get us through this thing somehow.
茱莉亚对这个风车的事有什么看法
What's Julia say about this windmill?
我不知道  因为茱莉亚不在这
Well, I don't know 'cause Julia's not here.
我在
I am.
但是我想我已经没权利发号施令了
But I guess I'm not supposed to give orders anymore.
我已经不在那个位子上了
That's apparently not my place.
那我们就用民主的方式来解决
So, let's do it democratically.
支持这个水雾扩散系统
All those in favor of the mist dispersal system,
愿意做点实事而不是干坐着的人
doing something instead of nothing,
请举手
raise your hand.
谁赞成让吉姆闭嘴
Everyone in favor of Jim shutting up
我们静静地等待风暴过去
while we wait the storm out?
好啊
Great.
你去哪
Where you going?
不去有狂风  血雨
Neither wind nor rain
该死的风暴的地方
nor creepy-ass dust.
乔
Joe!
诺莉
Norrie!
乔
Joe?
波琳画的
Pauline did that.
对吧
Didn't she?
是的
Yeah.
想到你竟然活在好久之前
It's so strange to think you were alive
感觉好奇怪
all those years ago.
而且你在我妈妈还是少女的时候就认识她
And that you knew my mom when she was a girl.
她是我搬到这里后交的第一个朋友
She was the first friend I made when I moved here.
她那时是什么样
What was she like?
很开心
Cheerful.
很勇敢
Really brave.
我很遗憾她很不开心地去世了
I'm sorry she died so unhappy.
我当时应该在这里
I should've been here.
陪着她
For her.
你也帮不了什么
It's not like you could help it.
你能保守秘密吗
Can you keep a secret?
能
Yes.
你见到每个男人都投怀送抱吗
Do you hit on literally everyone?
-我不是  -不用回答了
- I wasn't... - Don't answer.
-那是夸张  -诺莉  你怎么哭了
- It was rhetorical. - Norrie, why are you crying?
乔在哪
Where's Joe?
-走了  -去哪了
- Gone. - Gone where?
我不知道  你高兴了吧
I don't know! Are you happy?
诺莉  莱尔跑掉了
Norrie, Lyle's on the loose
他要追杀四只手
and he's coming after the four hands.
我们要在他之前找到乔
We have to find Joe before he does.
那还站在这干嘛
And we're just standing here?!
抱歉  我以为你是莱尔
Sorry, I thought you were Lyle.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我们不是说好分头行动吗
I thought we were trying to cover more ground.
是的
We are.
但你却绕回来跟踪我
But then you double back and you follow me?
你说什么呢  我是往右边走的
What are you talking about? I went right.
你怎么会在我前面
How did you get in front of me?
我往左边走的
I-I-I went left.
我们继续吧
Let's keep going.
或许你能让我对一件事安心一点
Maybe you can put my mind at ease about something.
怎么了
What's up?
安琪·麦卡利斯特死的那晚你在哪里
Where were you the night that Angie McAlister died?
你开玩笑呢吧
Are you kidding me?
回答我的问题
Just answer my question.
我当时在找梅兰妮
I was looking for Melanie.
这就很有趣了
See, that's funny.
因为当昨天我们知道她叫梅兰妮时
Because I haven't seen you all day,
我已经一整天没见过你了
when we just found out that her name was Melanie yesterday.
-小詹姆斯告诉我的  -不  他没有
- Junior told me. - No, he didn't.
你二十五年前就认识她了
You knew her 25 years ago.
茱莉亚把她从湖里
And you've known who she is
救起的时候你就知道她是谁
since Julia rescued her from the lake,
只是你什么都没有说
only you didn't say a word to anyone.
你为什么不说  山姆
Why didn't you say anything, Sam?
说梅兰妮起死回生了吗
About Melanie being back from the dead?
你告诉我我该怎么说
You tell me how to start that conversation.
好吧  你能不能
All right, you know what? Would you just
先回答你一直在回避的问题
answer the question that you keep dodging?
你
Where...?
你想说谢谢吗
You gonna say thank you?
那是莱尔的吗
That Lyle's?
一定是
Has to be.
你觉得他是从这里出去的吗
You think he went out this way?
我觉得如果从这里出去
I think you go out that way,
你就永远回不来了
you go out forever.
乔  你在这吗
Joe, are you in here?!
谢天谢地  你个蠢蛋
Oh, thank God! You idiot!
我们担心死你了  到处找你
We were worried about you. We looked all over.
我能照顾我自己
I can take care of myself.
可是莱尔想杀了我们
Not with Lyle wanting to kill us.
他想除掉四只手
He wants the four hands dead.
所以才杀了安琪
That's why he killed Angie.
是因为这个吗
That's the reason?
那或许我该谢谢他
Maybe I should thank him then.
什么
What?
安琪现在解脱了
Angie's out now.
或许我们也只有这样才能出去
Maybe that's the only way any of us are gonna get out.
我就没有
It didn't work for me.
我死了  又回来了
I died. I came back.
她会吗
Will she?
我过了一段时间才回来
It took awhile for me.
我觉得穹顶选择我们大家是有原因的
I think the dome choose all of us for something.
我们现在要勇敢面对
And now we have to deal with it.
齐心协力想办法
We need to figure it out together.
抱歉  梅兰妮  我觉得我们不能妄动
I'm sorry, Melanie. I think we need to stay put.
安琪会想让我保证你们安全的
Angie would want me to keep you all safe.
不
No.
安琪会想要答案
Angie would've wanted answers.
除非得到答案  否则她不会罢休
She wouldn't have stopped till she got them.
小詹姆斯  我们必须这样
Junior, we have to do this.
我情愿冒险
I would rather risk
再死一次  也不愿继续蒙在鼓里了
dying again than not knowing why I'm here any longer.
你知道该从哪开始吗
Do you have any idea where to start?
那个湖
The lake.
从那里开始
We start there.
你觉得莱尔跳下去了吗
You think Lyle jumped?
反正不是爬下去的
Well, he sure as hell didn't climb down.
或许他又回去了
Hey, you know what? Maybe he went right back there.
走了另一条路
Got out that way.
我说了  我向右走的
I told you, I went right--
还是回了你那里
it brought me back to you.
我没听见它碰到了东西
I didn't hear it hit anything.
这东西肯定深不见底
This thing must be deep as hell.
这里有问题
Something's off here.
真是保守的说法
Understatement.
考虑到我们刚走了那么远
I mean, given how far we just walked,
应该已经到穹顶边上了
we should've hit the dome wall by now.
或许穹顶没降下那么深
Maybe the dome doesn't come down this far?
可我们掌握的一切都表明它有这么深
Except that everything we know about it says that it does.
你确定你刚才是向右走的吗
You're sure you went right back there?
你猜怎么着  伙计
Hey, you know what, man?
我受够你说我骗人了
I'm sick of you calling me a liar.
又有谁知道你的底细
Who the hell knows your story anyway?
你和穹顶同一天出现
You show up the day the dome does.
没人知道你从哪来  你也不说
No one knows where you came from and you don't say.
难道不该你告诉我怎么回事吗
Well, shouldn't you be telling me what's going on?
你可是从1988年就知道蛋的事了
'Cause you've known about the egg since 1988
你和梅兰妮  莱尔  波琳
when you and Melanie, Lyle, Pauline,
一起发现的
when you all found it?
你还有所隐瞒
You know more than you're saying.
你也是
Well, that makes two of us.
找到水泥厂的地图了吗
Did you find the cement factory maps?
我直接拿了一切  然后带过来了
Just grabbed everything and brought them.
上面的土跟外面差不多了
This is almost as bad as outside.
说实话  茱莉亚  这沙尘暴我在行
Honestly, Julia, the storm is more my area.
是啊  是科学你都在行
Oh, yes, all science is your area.
我是切斯特磨坊镇的老师
I'm a teacher in Chester's Mill.
不是洛克希德的工程师
I'm not an engineer for Lockheed.
我知道自己有多大本事
I am all too aware of my limits.
我也知道你能闯多大祸
And I know what kind of damage you're capable of.
你不相信我吗
You don't trust me?
我原谅你
I forgave you.
那不是一回事
That's not the same thing.
来看看吧
Here we go.
图上说了水泥厂
Except this says the cement factory
根本没延伸到学校下面
never extended under the school.
还差很远
Nowhere even in the vicinity.
那是谁进了学校地下室挖的地道
So, who the hell went into the school basement and dug a tunnel?
为什么要挖
And why?
重要的是现在没有别的路下去了
All that matters right now is there's no other way down there.
也不知道怎么救出芭比和山姆
And no way to rescue Barbie and Sam that we know of.
除非炸掉塌方
Unless we blast the blockage.
如果他们被碎石压住了呢
And if they're pinned by debris?
或者也被炸死
They get blasted, too?
小詹姆斯说他向他们喊话了
Junior said he yelled at them.
我们可以告诉他们别靠近我们
We can tell them not to stand next to the thing
要炸的地方
we're gonna blow up.
你有更好的办法吗
You got a better idea?
本
Ben!
快坐下
Sit down!
本尼  外面怎么样  亲爱的
Benny! What is it, hon?
他喘不过气了
He can't breathe!
给
Oh, here!
-喝口水  -喝水没用
- Get some water. - Water's not gonna help him.
他需要吸入器
He needs his inhaler.
没事的  亲爱的
Oh, it's okay, honey.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
再来一次
One more.
外面的情况没有好转  伙计们
Outside's not getting any better, folks.
很快  我们所有人都会没法呼吸
Pretty soon, none of us are gonna be able to breathe.
有人想再投一次票吗
Anybody want to put it to another vote?
我加入
I'm down.
都是因为茱莉亚  对吧
This is about Julia, isn't it?
你一直疑神疑鬼的
All this suspicious crap.
如果这能让你心里舒服点
If it makes you feel any better,
我们之间什么都没发生
nothing happened.
是啊  有件事你说对了
Yeah, you're right about one thing.
我不喜欢让你和茱莉亚来往
I don't like you hanging around Julia
是因为我觉得你卑鄙至极
'cause I think you're shady as hell.
但现在  我们都被困在悬崖这儿
But right now, we're both stuck on some cliff,
不如你先闭嘴  让我考虑下现在的处境
so how about you shut up and let me think about that?
我们怎么可能穿过了穹顶壁
How the hell could we be passed the dome wall?
那怎么会我向左走  你向右走
How can I go left and you go right,
结果却在同一处相遇
somehow we both end up in the same place?
就好像有东西想让我们来这里一样
It's like something wanted us to end up here.
它就要这样了结我吗
Is this how it's finally gonna do me in,
把我逼疯
by driving me out of my mind?
这个该死的穹顶只带来了痛苦
The only thing this damn dome's ever done is bring pain!
我在湖边看到梅兰妮时  我以为我疯了
I thought I was crazy when I first saw Melanie back at the lake.
我一直在想着她们绝不可能
I just kept thinking there's no way
是同一人
it could be the same girl.
但她们确实是
Except it is.
她死的那晚到底发生了什么  山姆
What happened the night that she died, Sam?
不关你的事
None of your business.
你可以在这里告诉我  或者等我掐着你脖子
Well, you can tell me here or you can tell me in jail
把你从这里拖出去  你再在监狱里告诉我
after I've hauled you out of here by your throat.
我能想到你隐瞒的唯一原因
Only reason I can think of as to why you'd hide it...
就是是你杀了梅兰妮
you killed Melanie.
我干了什么不用你告诉我
Don't tell me what I did!
我爱过她
I loved her!
-那你就告诉我你做了什么  -你想知道吗
- Well, then, you tell me what you did! - You want to know?
那晚我们找到了陨石
The night we found the meteorite,
我们所有人都难以置信
none of us could believe it.
然后我们发现里面有颗蛋
And then we found the egg inside.
梅兰妮说除了她之外  其他人都很害怕
Melanie said everybody was scared of it except her.
我们都以为它很危险
We all thought it was dangerous!
我只是觉得不该碰它
I just wanted to leave it the hell alone!
但梅兰妮认为它需要保护
But Melanie decided that it needed to be protected.
感觉它好像有生命
That it was alive somehow.
而且它很害怕
And scared.
那她最后怎么会死
How did she end up dead?
那颗蛋开始发出声音
The egg started screaming.
波琳抱住自己的头
Pauline grabbed her head
说"我难受死了"
and said, "It's killing me""
莱尔急疯了
Lyle flipped.
说"我们得帮帮波琳"
Said, "We got to help Pauline""
我想抢那颗蛋
I tried to get the egg,
但梅兰妮就是不放手
but Melanie wouldn't let it go.
莱尔去追她
Lyle went after her.
我没阻止
I let him.
他推了她
He pushed her,
之后她摔入了陨石坑
and she fell into the crater.
她的头撞到了陨石
Her head hit the meteorite.
我们吓坏了
We panicked.
波琳求我帮帮莱尔
Pauline begged me to help Lyle.
我照做了
I did.
我把我此生挚爱丢在了坑里
I left the love of my life in a hole,
就像丢弃垃圾一样
like garbage.
而现在她回来了
And now she's back.
好了  数到三我们把它吊上去
All right, let's hoist it on three--
一  二  三
one, two, three!
使劲
Come on!
加油
芭比  你能听到吗
Barbie? Can you hear me?
山姆
Sam?
也许他们往深处走了
Maybe they moved on.
碳酸氢钠
你知道多少种杀人方法
How many different ways do you know to kill someone?
实践才是硬道理
It's how I apply it that counts.
在救他们出来之前
Can you not blow us up
能先别把我们自己炸飞吗
before we save them?
我正在努力
Yeah, I'm trying.
你在高中都教些什么
What are you doing teaching high school?
你是想问我是怎么搞砸自己的人生的
You mean how'd I screw up my life?
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
在我来切斯特磨坊镇前
I was headed to Cornell
我本打算去康奈尔大学念书
before I came to Chester's Mill.
为什么改变主意了
Why the change?
我爸爸病了
My dad got sick.
在他去世之前我得照顾他
I had to take care of him before he died.
你的故事估计跟我也差不多
Can't be all that different from your story.
你原来是名记者  对吧
You were a journalist, right?
来切斯特磨坊镇是你梦想中的工作吗
Was Chester's Mill your dream job?
-不  不是  -我说吧
- No, it wasn't. - See?
我们两个都不想来这儿
Neither of us wanted to be here.
但我们现在却在这儿
But we are.
这不是命运
It's not fate.
我们做了选择  然后来到了这里
We made choices and we ended up here.
如果我没照顾我爸爸的话
Maybe I could've helped a lot more people
也许我能帮助更多的人
if I hadn't helped my dad.
但往事不可逆
But that wasn't gonna happen.
所以我们就得做这事
So, you and me are stuck doing this.
你为什么要和吉姆合作
Why'd you work with Jim?
因为我觉得他的心眼还是很好的
Because I thought his heart was in the right place.
我搞错了
I was wrong about that.
我觉得我没看错你
I don't think I'm wrong about you.
小心点
Careful.
灰尘消散了
The dust cleared out.
是啊  现在该怎么办
Yeah. So, what now?
已经过去了几个小时
It's been hours.
那颗蛋知道我们在这
The egg knows we're here.
我能感受到
I can feel it.
它好像是在等着
It's like it's waiting.
我只知道这颗蛋不肯现身
All I know, this egg isn't showing itself.
就算我们都在
Even with all of us here.
也许我们要一起做一件事
Maybe we have to do something together.
什么事
Like what?
比如安琪还在的时候
Like when Angie was here,
我们一起触碰了迷你穹顶
and we all touched the mini-dome?
梅兰妮是最初的四只手之一
Melanie was one of the original four hands.
也许她还算数
Maybe she still counts.
所以安琪是可以取代的吗
So Angie's replaceable?!
没人要取代你姐姐
No one's replacing your sister.
但诺莉说得对
But Norrie's right.
反正也没别的主意了
I don't hear any other ideas.
起作用了
It's working!
为什么现在梅兰妮回来了
So, why's Melanie back now?
来吓唬我吗
To haunt me?
带给大家更多痛苦吗
To bring everyone more pain?
穹顶之下不都是痛苦
It's not all pain under this thing.
就是
The hell it's not.
每天就是新的噩梦
Every day is a new nightmare.
穹顶是一种缓慢的死刑
Dome's a slow execution for everyone in here.
你最应该清楚
You of all people should know that.
是啊  但我会面对
Yeah, but I deal with it.
你寻找让...
You look for what makes...
让继续生活下去值得的东西
what makes going on worth it.
比如说茱莉亚
Take Julia.
跟她在一起...
Being with her, that's...
那是让我改邪归正的机会
it's a chance for me to be good.
穹顶也让我害怕  但是
The dome scares me, too, but...
不全是痛苦
...it's not all pain.
有时候我会看见梅兰妮的脸出现在黑暗中
Sometimes I see Melanie's face in the dark...
开始流血不止
with the blood starting to pour out.
如果我能改变生命中的一件事
If I could change one thing in my life,
那就是那件
that'd be it.
我知道你的感受
Yeah, I know how you feel.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你杀了谁
Who'd you kill?
很多人
A lot of people.
鉴于目前的形势
Given the way things are going...
我知道我会再次杀人
...I know it's gonna happen again.
我不想那样做  但是...
I mean, I don't want that, but...
有时候你看见他们的脸
Sometimes you see their faces...
你开始想
...you wonder...
他们会在另一边等你吗
Are they gonna be waiting for you on the other side?
是啊
Yeah.
那天  我发现她在这边等我
The other day, I found her waiting for me on this side.
我能对她说什么
What the hell can I say to her?
我们离开这里
We get out of here,
也许你可以试试
maybe you can give it a try.
我知道梅兰妮最想知道答案
I know Melanie just wants answers more than anything.
至于25年前你们之前
As far as what happened between you two
发生的事  那是你们的事
25 years ago, you know, that's between you and her.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你没让我摔下去
Thanks for not letting me fall.
那不是岩石造成的
Hey, those aren't from rocks.
那些抓伤是怎么来的  山姆
Where'd you get those scratches, Sam?
把这个放在那边
Put that there.
这个刚好能放进这里
And this one will fit right here.
我来连接导火线
And I connect the fuse.
感谢道路维修部门
Thank God for the department of roads and repair.
你在祈祷吗
You praying?
不  但我很希望这能管用
No. But I hope to God this works.
芭比
Barbie!
山姆  如果你们能听到
Sam! If you can hear me,
尽可能后退
get way, way back!
我们开始吧
Okay. Let's do this.
回到入口处
Back to the entrance, right.
好
Okay.
那些是防卫伤口
Those are defensive wounds.
指甲抓的
From fingernails.
你开玩笑呢  对吧
You're kidding, right?
安琪是个斗士
Angie was a fighter.
她留下了一点凶手的战利品
She got a piece of whoever tried to kill her.
-她指甲下的皮肤证明了这一点  -芭比
- The skin under her fingernails showed that. - Barbie...
你杀了她  山姆
You killed her, Sam.
不是莱尔  而是你
Not Lyle. You.
而你做的一切
And everything that you've done
都把责任推到他身上去
has been to put the blame back on to him.
他是个疯子
The guy's a maniac!
你看见他对丽贝卡做的事了
You saw what he did to Rebecca!
他还攻击了我侄子
And he attacked my nephew!
你杀了你侄子爱过的一个19岁的姑娘
You killed a 19-year-old girl that your nephew loved!
我必须如此
I had to!
波琳写进日记里的一切都成真了
Everything Pauline put in her journal has come true.
上面写着如果那四个小孩死了
It says in here that if those four kids die,
穹顶就会落下
the dome comes down!
我必须做出这个牺牲  来拯救大伙儿
It's a sacrifice I have to make to save everyone!
你甚至愿意杀了小詹姆斯
You would even kill Junior?
到了某个时刻  我必须如此
At some point I'll have to!
我会完结这一切  终获自由
I'll finish it, and I'll finally be free!
然后我会自杀
Then I will kill myself.
或者你来杀了我
Or you can kill me.
我会为此感谢你的
Hell, I'll thank you for it.
你不会在黑暗中看见我的脸
You will never see my face in the dark.
我发誓
I swear.
你不许碰那些孩子
You're not even gonna touch those kids.
我要抓住你
I'm taking you in.
你所得的正义
And your justice is gonna be
是小詹姆斯知道这事后对你采取的行为
whatever Junior does to you once he finds out.
她还不错
She's not so bad.
现在你信她了吗
Now you believe her?
是
Yes.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为什么
For what?
我没有让你歇口气
For not giving you a break
而我妈妈去世后  你让我歇了口气
like you gave me after my mom died.
很抱歉我让你觉得我不爱你
I'm sorry I ever made you feel like I didn't love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
门窗都锁好了
Okay, everything's locked up.
你觉得莱尔在跟踪我们吗
Do you think Lyle's following us?
我不知道  我只是谨慎为妙
I don't know. I'm just being careful.
你们准备好了吗
You guys ready?
好了
Yeah.
让我们搞清楚吧
Let's find out.
粉色星星
Pink stars.
跟我们之前看到的一样
Like we saw before.
我梦里看见
I saw that in my dream.
我也看过
I've seen it, too.
多年以前
Years ago.
在我的家乡
It's in my hometown.
齐尼斯
Zenith.
但这是什么意思
Yeah, but what does it mean?
这是正确的选择  对吧
This is the right call, isn't it?
他们很聪明  对吧
They're smart guys, right?
会知道要和
They'll know to put some space
塌方保持距离的
between them and the blockage.
他们不会受伤的
They won't be hurt.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
我信任你
I trust you.
你在干什么
Hey. What are you doing?
你不会让我完成必须做的事  所以那靠你了
You'll never let me finish what I have to, so it's on you now.
我不在乎你活着还是死去
I don't care if you live or die.
但如果你还有一点点是非观
But if you got any sense of right and wrong left,
你就要直视小詹姆斯  告诉他发生的事
you're gonna look Junior in the face and tell him what you did.
拿着吧
Take it.
等时辰到了  你会需要的
When the time comes, you'll need it.
你欠小詹姆斯真相
You owe Junior the truth!
你会看到的
You'll see.
都是痛苦
It's all pain.
当你看到许多人死去
When you watch enough people die,
看到茱莉亚死去
when you watch Julia die,
你会自己杀了那些孩子
you will put the knife to those kids yourself!
我累坏了  芭比
I'm so tired, Barbie.
山姆
Sam.
Sam!
没看见芭比或者山姆
No sign of Barbie or Sam.
他们肯定在这里面
They've got to be in here somewhere.
茱莉亚
Julia!
今天做了件好事  吉姆
Did a good thing today, Jim.
帮帮忙其实是种慰藉
Well, honestly, it's a relief just to lend a hand.
我们今天都有值得骄傲的事  对吧
I think we all have something to be proud of today, right?
真正的问题是
The real question is
茱莉亚一天都去哪儿了
where's Julia been all day?
我听说芭比在中学那边
Well, I heard that Barbie got into some kind of trouble
碰到了难题
over at the high school.
她决定帮助他  而不是帮我们
She decided to help him instead of pitching in with us.
不是吧
Well, you don't say?
我想有时候真爱
I guess, sometimes love
胜过了恪尽职守
wins out over doing your job.
芭比
Barbie!
谢天谢地你没事
Thank God! Oh, you're okay.
是啊
Yeah.
山姆呢
Where's Sam?
他走了
He's gone.